RESEARCH STATEMENT

As a prospective Ph.D. student, my research interests lie at the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), health and wellbeing, and participatory design. Using qualitative methods, I investigate how technology can navigate cultural, social and personal factors to support health and wellbeing. As part of this research, I both investigate individuals' experiences and design, develop, and evaluate systems. I am particularly interested in themes of collaboration and marginalization, and the contexts of mental health and health activism.

EDUCATION

2020 – Dec 2023 (Expected) B.S., Informatics, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Thesis: Supporting Technologically-Facilitated Reflection on Bereavement Experiences

Advisor: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung Minors: Human-Centered Computing, English

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE -

Undergraduate Researcher, Proactive Health Informatics, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Sep 2022 -

Probing the Role of Technology in Pro-Choice Abortion Activism

Present

Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Dr. Elizabeth Kaziunas, Dr. Katie Siek

Co-led a study investigating technological needs of pro-choice Indiana abortion activists. Designed cultural probe with participatory methods, and currently planning second study mapping the sociotechnical space of Indiana abortion activism via probe.

May 2022 -Present Supporting Technologically-Facilitated Reflection on Bereavement Experiences

Advisor: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung

Co-led a study investigating opportunities for reflective systems to support bereaved individuals. Designed and conducted qualitative diary and interview study.

Sep 2021 -Present Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences

Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Aswati Panicker

Continued previous REU project; assisted with finalizing probe design and provided design input during probe development. Currently planning field deployment.

May - July 2021

REU Research Intern, Proactive Health Informatics REU Site, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Aswati Panicker

Assisted with the design of a cultural probe investigating the digital sharing of cooking experiences between distanced family members. Conducted user research, iteratively designed probe, and conducted usability testing.

Jan – May 2021 **Undergraduate Research Assistant**, Undergraduate Research Opportunities in Computing (UROC), Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Influence of Conspiracy Theories on Human Information Interactions

Advisor: Dr. Devan Donaldson

Assisted with paper revisions and journal re-submission. Conducted literature review, wrote paper sections, and conducted data re-analysis.

PUBLICATIONS -

Refereed Conference Posters

2023 "I Don't Need a Megaphone to Be Helpful": Probing the Role of Technology in Pro-Choice Abortion Activism

Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing

<u>Colin LeFevre</u>, Aswati Panicker, Sitha Vallabhaneni, Nikhil Dinesh, Forum Modi, Katie Siek, and Chia-Fang Chung

2022 Cooking Stories: Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences

European Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work

Forum Modi, Colin LeFevre, Nikhil Dinesh, Aswati Panicker, and Chia-Fang Chung

Refereed Journal Articles

2022 Records, trust, and misinformation: Using birtherism to understand the influence of conspiracy theories on human information interactions

Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology

Devan Donaldson and Colin LeFevre

Lightly Reviewed Workshop Papers

2023 "A Safe Space to Think About Grief": Reflecting on Bereavement Through Video Games and Experiential Metaphor

Workgroup on Interactive Systems in Healthcare (WISH) Symposium, Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

Colin LeFevre and Chia-Fang Chung

TEACHING EXPERIENCE -

Spring 2022, Fall 2022, Spring 2023 **Undergraduate Instructor**, Department of Informatics, Indiana University

Bloomington, USA

INFO-I 300 Introduction to Human Computer Interaction

Instructors of Record: Dr. Phil Jordan, Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung

Closely mentored groups of 10-15 students on user research, ideation, and prototyping. Created comprehensive set of tutorials on UX / UI prototyping software (Figma). Coordinated weekly instructional team meetings and led grader training.

	HONORS & AWARDS
	Indiana University Bloomington
2020 – Present	Luddy & Provost Scholar
2020 – Present	Luddy School Dean's List
2022, 2023	Luddy Undergraduate Instructor Teaching Excellence Award
	SERVICE —
	Indiana University Bloomington
2022 - Present	Student Representative, Informatics Undergraduate Curriculum Committee
	ACM Conferences
2023	Student Volunteer (In-Person), Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing
2023	External Reviewer, Posters (x1), Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing
2023	Student Volunteer (In-Person), Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems
	— SKILLS —————

HCI Research

Interviews, Cultural Probes, Diary Studies, Ethnography, Participatory Design, Qualitative Coding, Thematic Analysis

UX Design

Iterative Design, User Research, User Personas, Protoyping, Usability Testing, Affinity Mapping

Tools

Google Workspace, Figma, Miro, Overleaf, Saturate, Taguette, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Native